

**FULL STACK ENGINEER** 

## **Details**

Via Montecchia, 22/A Selvazzano Dentro (PD), 35030 Italy +39 340 07 07 596

NATIONALITY

marco.tisi@gmail.com

Italian

# Links

Linkedin

### **Skills**

React

Gatsby

NextJS

Storybook

Node

Laravel Framework

GraphQL

SQL and NoSQL DBs

Amazon AWS

Test Driven Development

Agile Development

Remote Working

#### Languages

Italian - Native

English - C1

Spanish - B1

## **Hobbies**

Travelling, trekking, photography and music are my passions.

## **Profile**

Remote Full-Stack Engineer with experience in building eCommerce platforms, CMSs and web applications. Skilled in JavaScript (Typescript, Node.js, React, Gatsby), PHP (Laravel, Symfony) and DevOps (AWS, Docker, Terraform). Experienced in Object Oriented Programming and Functional Programming. Always enjoying learning about new technologies, frameworks and languages.

# **Employment History**

#### Lead Frontend Engineer, Amazee Labs AG, Zurich

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

Planning and building medium to large websites using React, Gatsby and NextJS. Writing integrations to fetch content from CMS to web applications. Leading a team of developers to achieve goals, raise knowledge, leverage best practices and review code. Collaborating with the accessibility team to ensure that websites follow standards. Crafting internal projects to test new technologies, libraries or approaches. Working with the management to define company goals.

### Full Stack Engineer, Headstart, London

JUNE 2019 - JUNE 2020

Working fully remote in the Engineering Team to develop and maintain core API written in Node using FeathersJS and MongoDB. Developing and maintaining applications which interact with the API built with React and Redux, developing side projects and microservices using NestJS. Managing corporate infrastructure in AWS using Docker, Terraform and CircleCI.

#### Head of Research & Development, Workup, Bassano del Grappa

OCTOBER 2016 - DECEMBER 2018

Planning and developing the corporate flagship product, a modular CMS / B2B / B2C platform, by researching new technologies and finding the appropriate team to achieve the goals set by the company and in line with the business requirements, working almost fully remote.

- Planning, estimation and development of the product using Laravel
  5.1+, VueJs, Vanilla ES6, NodeJS, Webpack, UIKit, Less, MySQL, Redis and
  Composer private repositories;
- Introducing Agile Scrum methodology to ensure rapid and focused development with Atlassian Jira, Version Control System with Atlassian BitBucket and Continuous Integration with Atlassian Bamboo to improve the entire lifecycle of the product;
- Planning, creation and maintenance of the auto-scaled AWS Ubuntu-based LEMP production stack, using Vagrant, Docker, EC2, S3, CodeDeploy, CloudFront, ElastiCache and Aurora;
- Interviewing, recruiting and guiding new talents to join the R&D team, attending local and international conferences and workshops, encouraging best practices and sharing of knowledges.

#### Senior Web Developer, Workup, Bassano del Grappa

FEBRUARY 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2016

Planning, estimation and development of corporate, B2B and B2C websites using the corporate PHP CMS.

- Planning, estimation and development of websites, in accordance with customers goals;
- Dealing with customers to assists in new features, improvements and fixes;
- Mantaining and updating the corporate CMS, proposing new features and plugins to increase productivity and value;
- Communication and collaboration with others teams to ensure that goals are achieved.

#### Senior Web Developer, Atena.net, Vicenza

JUNE 2012 - FEBRUARY 2014

Team leader responsible for the development and maintenance of the corporate e-commerce website.

- Planning and creating entire website from scratch with CakePHP, jQuery,
  Backbone, Undescore and Twitter Bootstrap;
- Supporting the team by ensuring appropriate coordination and communication between the team and the external associates;
- Integration of the website with CRMs and other external tools;
- Communication and collaboration with the Marketing Team to help acquire more customers;
- Creation of Facebook Apps to raise the number of fans.

## Phonegap Developer, BlackBeardCrew

JUNE 2013 - JUNE 2013

Planning and developing a series of PhoneGap Application for the aviation industry with a small crew of friends.

## Web Developer, Atenet, Vicenza

JULY 2005 - JUNE 2012

Developing corporate intranet ERP and its integration with pre-existent Management Software. Developing B2B sites for the acquisition and tracking of customer's orders.

## Education

Bachelor Degree in Sound Engineer, Conservatorio C. Pollini, Padova 2008 – 2013

## **Publications**

# 3D Audio on Mobile Environment using OpenFrameworks, Padova

2013 - 2013

Thesis about user interaction in 3D Sound on Mobile Environment using OpenFrameworks. The purpose of this thesis is to explore the techniques currently available for offering users a sound closer to what the eye sees, introducing the binaural audio system and subsequently guiding the preparation and development of an application that can be run on Linux and Android.

## **Honours and Awards**

StartCup Veneto - 1st Prize, Padova

2010 - 2010

SaMPL, composed by Federico Avanzini, Sergio Canazza, Nicola Bernardini, Francesco Morosinotto, Marco Tisi won the first prize. The business plan covers a software that extracts the audio signal from a picture of a phonograph record, reconstructing the sound recorded in the old vinyl with a non-invasive method. It is intended for music archives in digital libraries and also to individuals who own a lot of records and want to play them on a digital reader.